const data = [
  {
    question:
      'What is the third angle for the triangle where angle1 = 45Â° and angle2 = 45Â°?',
    options: ['45Â°', '30Â°', '60Â°', '90Â°'],
    correctOption: 'd',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the type of the triangle when angle1 = 45Â° and angle2 = 45Â°?',
    options: ['obtuse', 'acute', 'right'],
    correctOption: 'c',
  },
  {
    question: 'A triangle can have ______',
    options: ['one right angle', 'two right angles'],
    correctOption: 'aÂ°',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which of the following sides can form a right angled triangle?',
    options: ['14, 15, 26', '1, 2, 3', '12, 16, 20', '5, 7, 8'],
    correctOption: 'c',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which of the following triangles are always similar?',
    options: [
      'Equilateral triangle',
      'Isosceles triangle',
      'Right angled Triangle',
    ],
    correctOption: 'a',
  },
  {
    question:
      'If one angle of a triangle is obtuse, then which one of the following is the possible measure of remaining angles?',
    options: ['100Â°', '85Â°', '35Â°'],
    correctOption: 'a',
  },
  {
    question:
      'If the largest angle in a triangle is 70Â°, what is the least possible value of the smallest angle of the triangle?',
    options: ['30Â°', '10Â°'],
    correctOption: 'a',
  },
  {
    question: 'The perimeter of scalene triangle with sides a, b, c is _____',
    options: ['a + b + c', '2a', 'None of these'],
    correctOption: 'a',
  },
  {
    question: 'A scalene triangle has ___ lines of symmetry',
    options: ['2', 'no', '15'],
    correctOption: 'b',
  },
  {
    question:
      'There is a right triangle PQR where: angle Q = 90Â°; angle P = angle R. What is the measure of angles P and R?',
    options: ['85Â°', '65Â°', '45Â°'],
    correctOption: 'c',
  },
];

function alertMsg(type, msg, ms) {
  const tID = setInterval(() => {
    alertText.innerText = msg;
    alertText.classList.add(`alert-${type}`);
    alertText.classList.add('show-alert');
  }, 0);

  setTimeout(() => {
    clearInterval(tID);
    alertText.classList.remove(`alert-${type}`);
    alertText.classList.remove('show-alert');
  }, ms);
}

const quizCenter = document.querySelector('.questions-center');
const output = document.querySelector('.output-section');
const alertText = document.querySelector('.alert');

function charToNum(char) {
  return char.toUpperCase().charCodeAt(0) - 65;
}

function displayQuiz(quizData) {
  const myQuizes = quizData
    .map(({ question, options, correctOption }, i) => {
      return `
    <article class="question-article">
      <p>Q.${i + 1} ${question}</p>
      <div class="options-div" data-ans="${options[charToNum(correctOption)]}">
      ${[...options]
        .map((option, j) => {
          return `          
          <label for="${i + 1}${j + 1}">
            <input type="radio" name="question-${
              i + 1
            }" value="${option}" id="${i + 1}${j + 1}" /> ${option}</label>
        `;
        })
        .join('')}
      </div>
    </article>
    `;
    })
    .join('');

  quizCenter.innerHTML = `
  ${myQuizes}
  `;

  return quizCenter;
}

function handleSubmit(e) {
  e.preventDefault();
  console.log('Clicked', e.target);
  let score = 0;
  const formData = new FormData(e.currentTarget);

  const userSelectedAns = [];
  for (const entry of formData.entries()) {
    userSelectedAns.push(entry);
  }
  const updatedUserSelectedAns = userSelectedAns.map(([questionNo, ans]) => {
    return [questionNo.split('-')[1], ans];
  });
  const userAns = Object.fromEntries(updatedUserSelectedAns);
  for (const single in userAns) {
    const indexToSearch = Number(single) - 1;
    const correctAns =
      data[indexToSearch].options[charToNum(data[indexToSearch].correctOption)];
    if (correctAns === userAns[single]) {
      score++;
    }
  }

  output.innerHTML = `
  Your score is <span style="color:${
    score > 5 ? 'green' : 'red'
  }">${score}</span> / ${data.length} ${score > 5 ? 'ðŸŽ‰' : 'ðŸ˜Ÿ'}
  `;

  alertMsg('success', 'Done âœ…', 1000);
}

function handleClear() {
  const allRadioInputs = document.querySelectorAll('[type="radio"]');
  allRadioInputs.forEach((input) => {
    input.checked = false;
  });
  output.innerHTML = '';
  alertMsg('success', 'Cleared', 1000);
}

window.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', () => {
  displayQuiz(data);
  const form = document.querySelector('.quiz-section');
  form.addEventListener('submit', handleSubmit);
});

document.querySelectorAll('.btn')[1].addEventListener('click', handleClear);

const header = document.querySelector('.header');

window.addEventListener('scroll', function () {
  const scrollHeight = window.scrollY;
  const headerHeight = header.getBoundingClientRect().height;
  if (scrollHeight > headerHeight) {
    header.classList.add('fixed-nav');
  } else {
    header.classList.remove('fixed-nav');
  }
});
